<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">

  <class>
    <name>Artificer</name>
    <hd>8</hd>

    <proficiency>Constitution, Intelligence, Arcana, History, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Sleight of Hand</proficiency>
    <numSkills>2</numSkills>

    <armor>Light armor, Medium armor, Shields</armor>
    <weapons>Simple weapons</weapons>
    <tools>Thieves' tools, Tinker's tools, Artisan's tools</tools>

    <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
    <spellbook>YES</spellbook>
    <spellList>Acid Splash, Booming Blade, Create Bonfire, Dancing Lights, Fire Bolt, Frostbite, Green-Flame Blade, Guidance, Light, Lightning Lure, Mage Hand, Magic Stone, Mending, Message, Poison Spray, Prestidigitation, Ray of Frost, Resistance, Shocking Grasp, Spare the Dying, Sword Burst, Thorn Whip, Thunderclap, Absorb Elements, Alarm, Catapult, Cure Wounds, Detect Magic, Disguise Self, Expeditious Retreat, Faerie Fire, False Life, Feather Fall, Grease, Identify, Jump, Longstrider, Purify Food and Drink, Sanctuary, Snare, Tasha's Caustic Brew, Aid, Alter Self, Arcane Lock, Blur, Continual Flame, Darkvision, Enhance Ability, Enlarge/Reduce, Heat Metal, Invisibility, Kinetic Jaunt, Lesser Restoration, Levitate, Magic Mouth, Magic Weapon, Protection from Poison, Pyrotechnics, Rope Trick, See Invisibility, Skywrite, Spider Climb, Vortex Warp, Web, Ashardalon's Stride, Blink, Catnap, Create Food and Water, Dispel Magic, Elemental Weapon, Flame Arrows, Fly, Gaseous Form, Glyph of Warding, Haste, Intellect Fortress, Protection from Energy, Revivify, Tiny Servant, Water Breathing, Water Walk, Arcane Eye, Elemental Bane, Fabricate, Freedom of Movement, Leomund's Secret Chest, Mordenkainen's Faithful Hound, Mordenkainen's Private Sanctum, Otiluke's Resilient Sphere, Stone Shape, Stoneskin, Summon Construct, Animate Objects, Bigby's Hand, Creation, Greater Restoration, Skill Empowerment, Transmute Rock, Wall of Stone</spellList>

    <!-- LEVEL 1 -->
    <autolevel level="1">
      <feature>
        <name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
        <text>Armor: Light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
        <text>Weapons: Simple weapons, firearms (optional)</text>
        <text>Tools: Thieves' tools, tinker's tools, one type of artisan's tools of your choice</text>
        <text>Saving Throws: Constitution, Intelligence</text>
        <text>Skills: Choose two skills from Arcana, History, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, and Sleight of Hand</text>
      </feature>

      <feature>
        <name>Starting Equipment</name>
        <text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
        <text />
        <text>• Any two simple weapons of your choice</text>
        <text>• A light crossbow and 20 bolts</text>
        <text>• Your choice of studded leather armor or scale mail</text>
        <text>• Thieves' tools and a dungeoneer's pack</text>
        <text />
        <text>Starting Wealth: 5d4 x 10 gp (average 125 gp)</text>
      </feature>

      <feature>
        <name>Magical Tinkering</name>
        <text>Imbue tiny objects with magical effects.</text>
      </feature>

      <feature>
        <name>Spellcasting</name>
        <text>You prepare spells equal to Intelligence modifier + half Artificer level.</text>
        <slots>2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 2 -->
    <autolevel level="2">
      <feature>
        <name>Infuse Item</name>
        <text>You can infuse items with magical properties.</text>

        <choice>
          <name>Infusions</name>

          <option>
            <name>Armor of Magical Strength</name>
            <text>Prerequisite: An armor. This armor has 6 charges. The wearer can expend a charge to add their Intelligence modifier to a Strength check or saving throw, or to avoid being knocked prone.</text>
          </option>

          <option>
            <name>Enhanced Arcane Focus</name>
            <text>Prerequisite: A rod, staff, or wand. While holding this item, a creature gains a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls, and ignores half cover when making a spell attack.</text>
          </option>

          <option>
            <name>Enhanced Defense</name>
            <text>+1 AC (scales later).</text>
          </option>

          <option>
            <name>Enhanced Weapon</name>
            <text>+1 attack/damage (scales later).</text>
          </option>

          <option>
            <name>Homunculus Servant</name>
            <text>Prerequisite: A gem or crystal worth at least 100 gp. You learn how to infuse a tiny mechanical homunculus to serve you as a companion. It obeys your commands (Bonus Action to command).</text>
          </option>

          <option>
            <name>Mind Sharpener</name>
            <text>Prerequisite: An armor or robe. This item has 4 charges. When the wearer fails a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration, they can use a reaction to expend a charge and succeed instead.</text>
          </option>

          <option>
            <name>Repeating Shot</name>
            <text>Ignores Loading, creates ammo.</text>
          </option>

          <option>
            <name>Returning Weapon</name>
            <text>Returns after throw.</text>
          </option>

          <option>
            <name>Repulsion Shield</name>
            <text>Push attacker using reaction (charges).</text>
          </option>

          <option>
            <name>Spell-Refueling Ring</name>
            <text>Recover spell slot (1/day).</text>
          </option>

        </choice>
      </feature>

      <feature>
        <name>Infusions Known</name>
        <text>4 infusions known.</text>
      </feature>

      <feature>
        <name>Infused Items</name>
        <text>2 active infusions.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 3 -->
    <autolevel level="3">
      <feature>
        <name>Artificer Subclass</name>
        <text>Select specialization (Alchemist, Armorer, Artillerist, Battle Smith, or Cartographer).</text>
      </feature>

      <!-- Alchemist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Specialist</name>
        <text>An Alchemist is an expert at combining exotic reagents to produce mystical effects. Alchemists use their creations to heal and protect, or to unleash acid and poison.

Tool Proficiency:
You gain proficiency with alchemist’s supplies. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of artisan’s tools of your choice.

Alchemist Spells:
You always have certain spells prepared after you reach specific levels in this class. These count as artificer spells for you, but they don’t count against the number of spells you can prepare.
- 3rd: healing word, ray of sickness
- 5th: flaming sphere, melf's acid arrow
- 9th: gaseous form, mass healing word
- 13th: blight, death ward
- 17th: cloudkill, raise dead

Experimental Elixir:
Whenever you finish a long rest, you can magically produce an experimental elixir in an empty flask of your choice. Roll on the Experimental Elixir table for the elixir's effect, which is triggered when someone drinks the elixir. As an action, a creature can drink the elixir or administer it to an incapacitated creature.
You can create additional experimental elixirs by expending a spell slot of 1st level or higher for each one. When you do so, you use your action to create the elixir in an empty flask of your choice, and you choose the elixir's effect from the Experimental Elixir table.

Experimental Elixir Table:
1 | Healing: The drinker regains hit points equal to 2d4 + your Intelligence modifier.
2 | Swiftness: The drinker's walking speed increases by 10 feet for 1 hour.
3 | Resilience: The drinker gains a +1 bonus to AC for 10 minutes.
4 | Boldness: The drinker can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to every attack roll and saving throw they make for the next minute.
5 | Flight: The drinker gains a flying speed of 10 feet for 10 minutes.
6 | Transformation: The drinker's body is transformed as if by the alter self spell (appearance change). The drinker determines the appearance.</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Healing Word</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Ray of Sickness</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Armorer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armorer Specialist</name>
        <text>An Artificer who specializes as an Armorer modifies armor to function almost like a second skin. The armor is enhanced to hone the artificer's magic, unleash potent attacks, and generate a formidable defense.

Tools of the Trade:
You gain proficiency with heavy armor and smith's tools. If you already have smith's tools proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of artisan's tools of your choice.

Armorer Spells:
You always have certain spells prepared after you reach specific levels in this class. These count as artificer spells for you, but they don’t count against the number of spells you can prepare.
- 3rd: magic missile, thunderwave
- 5th: mirror image, shatter
- 9th: hypnotic pattern, lightning bolt
- 13th: fire shield, greater invisibility
- 17th: passwall, wall of force

Arcane Armor:
Your metallurgical pursuits have led to you making your armor a conduit for your magic. As an action, you can turn a suit of armor you are wearing into Arcane Armor, provided you have smith's tools in hand. You gain the following benefits while wearing this armor:
- If the armor normally has a Strength requirement, the arcane armor ignores it.
- You can use the arcane armor as a spellcasting focus for your artificer spells.
- The armor attaches to you and can't be removed against your will. It also expands to cover your entire body, including any missing limbs, functioning identically to a limb it replaces.
- You can don or doff the armor as an action.
The armor continues to be Arcane Armor until you don another suit of armor or you die.

Armor Model:
You can customize your Arcane Armor. Choose one of the following models: Guardian or Infiltrator. The model you choose gives you special benefits while you wear it. You can change the armor's model whenever you finish a short or long rest, provided you have smith's tools in hand.

Guardian Model:
- Thunder Gauntlets: Each of the armor's gauntlets counts as a simple melee weapon while you aren't holding anything in it, and it deals 1d8 thunder damage on a hit. A creature hit by a gauntlet has disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you until the start of your next turn.
- Defensive Field: As a bonus action, you can gain temporary hit points equal to your level in this class. You can use this bonus action a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Infiltrator Model:
- Lightning Launcher: A gemlike node appears on one of your armored fists or on the chest. It counts as a simple ranged weapon, with a normal range of 90 feet and a long range of 300 feet, and it deals 1d6 lightning damage on a hit. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with it, you can deal an extra 1d6 lightning damage to that target.
- Powered Steps: Your walking speed increases by 5 feet.
- Dampening Field: You have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. If the armor normally imposes disadvantage on such checks, the advantage and disadvantage cancel each other out.</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Magic Missile</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Thunderwave</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Artillerist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artillerist Specialist</name>
        <text>An Artillerist specializes in using magic to hurl devastation on the battlefield. They use wands, staves, and magical cannons to dominate combat.

Tool Proficiency:
You gain proficiency with woodcarver’s tools. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of artisan’s tools of your choice.

Artillerist Spells:
You always have certain spells prepared after you reach specific levels in this class. These count as artificer spells for you, but they don’t count against the number of spells you can prepare.
- 3rd: shield, thunderwave
- 5th: scorching ray, shatter
- 9th: fireball, wind wall
- 13th: ice storm, wall of fire
- 17th: cone of cold, wall of force

Eldritch Cannon:
You can use your woodcarver's tools or smith's tools to magically summon a Small or Tiny eldritch cannon in an unoccupied space on a horizontal surface within 5 feet of you. A Small cannon occupies its space, and a Tiny cannon can be held in one hand. Once you create a cannon, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest or until you expend a spell slot of 1st level or higher. You can have only one cannon at a time and can't create one while your cannon is present.
The cannon is a magical object. It has an AC of 18 and a number of hit points equal to five times your artificer level. It is immune to poison damage and all conditions. If it is forced to make an ability check or a saving throw, treat all its ability scores as 10 (+0). If the mending spell is cast on it, it regains 2d6 hit points. It disappears if it is reduced to 0 hit points or after 1 hour. You can dismiss it early as an action.
When you create the cannon, you choose its type:
- Flamethrower: Exhales fire in an adjacent 15-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 2d8 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. The fire ignites any flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.
- Force Ballista: Make a ranged spell attack against one creature or object within 120 feet of the cannon. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 force damage, and if the target is a creature, it is pushed up to 5 feet away from the cannon.
- Protector: The cannon emits a burst of positive energy that grants itself and each creature of your choice within 10 feet of it a number of temporary hit points equal to 1d8 + your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).
On each of your turns, you can take a bonus action to cause the cannon to activate if you are within 60 feet of it. As part of the same bonus action, you can direct the cannon to walk or climb up to 15 feet to an unoccupied space, provided it has legs.</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Shield</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Thunderwave</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Battle Smith -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Battle Smith Specialist</name>
        <text>Armies put a lot of stock in strong defenses, but Battle Smiths believe that a strong defense is built around an active, aggressive presence on the battlefield.

Tools of the Trade:
You gain proficiency with smith's tools. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency with one other type of artisan's tools of your choice.

Battle Smith Spells:
You always have certain spells prepared after you reach specific levels in this class. These count as artificer spells for you, but they don’t count against the number of spells you can prepare.
- 3rd: heroism, shield
- 5th: branding smite, warding bond
- 9th: aura of vitality, conjure barrage
- 13th: aura of purity, fire shield
- 17th: banishing smite, mass cure wounds

Battle Ready:
You gain proficiency with martial weapons. In addition, when you attack with a magic weapon, you can use your Intelligence modifier, instead of Strength or Dexterity, for the attack and damage rolls.

Steel Defender:
Your metallurgical pursuits have led to you creating a steel defender, a faithful companion that accompanies you. It is friendly to you and your companions, and it obeys your commands.
In combat, the steel defender shares your initiative count, but it takes its turn immediately after yours. It can move and use its reaction on its own, but the only action it takes on its turn is the Dodge action, unless you take a bonus action on your turn to command it to take another action. That action can be one in its stat block or some other action. If you are incapacitated, the defender can take any action of its choice, not just Dodge.
If the mending spell is cast on the steel defender, it regains 2d6 hit points. If it has died within the last hour, you can use your smith's tools as an action to revive it, provided you are within 5 feet of it and you expend a spell slot of 1st level or higher. The steel defender returns to life with all its hit points restored.</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Heroism</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Shield</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Cartographer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cartographer Specialist</name>
        <text>A Cartographer Artificer focuses on navigation, battlefield positioning, and tactical support through magical maps.

Tools of the Trade:
You gain proficiency with Calligrapher's Supplies and Cartographer's Tools. In addition, when you scribe a Spell Scroll, the time required is halved.

Cartographer Spells:
You always have certain spells prepared after you reach specific levels in this class. These count as artificer spells for you, but they don't count against the number of spells you can prepare.
- 3rd: faerie fire, guiding bolt, healing word
- 5th: locate object, mind spike
- 9th: call lightning, clairvoyance
- 13th: banishment, locate creature
- 17th: scrying, teleportation circle

Adventurer's Atlas:
After a long rest, you can create magical maps for yourself and a number of allies equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 2 maps total). While carrying the map, a creature gains the following benefits:
- Awareness: Add 1d4 to Initiative rolls.
- Positioning: You know the exact location of all other map holders on the same plane.
- Tactical Targeting: Map holders can target each other with spells or beneficial effects regardless of sight or cover, provided they are within the effect's range.

Mapping Magic:
- Illuminated Cartography: You can cast Faerie Fire without expending a spell slot a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier, regaining all uses on a long rest.
- Portal Jump: On your turn, you can spend half your movement to teleport to an unoccupied space you can see within 10 feet, or within 5 feet of another map holder who is within 30 feet of you.</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Faerie Fire</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Guiding Bolt</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Healing Word</spell>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 4 -->
    <autolevel level="4">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 5 -->
    <autolevel level="5">
      <!-- Alchemist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Specialist (Level 5)</name>
        <text>Alchemical Savant:
Whenever you cast a spell using your alchemist's supplies as the spellcasting focus, you gain a bonus to one roll of the spell. That roll must restore hit points or be a damage roll that deals acid, fire, necrotic, or poison damage. The bonus equals your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).

Spells Prepared:
- Flaming Sphere
- Melf's Acid Arrow</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Flaming Sphere</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Melf's Acid Arrow</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Armorer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armorer Specialist (Level 5)</name>
        <text>Extra Attack:
You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.

Spells Prepared:
- Mirror Image
- Shatter</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Mirror Image</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Shatter</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Artillerist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artillerist Specialist (Level 5)</name>
        <text>Arcane Firearm:
You can turn a wand, staff, or rod into an arcane firearm, a conduit for your destructive spells. When you cast an artificer spell through the firearm, roll a d8, and you gain a bonus to one of the spell's damage rolls equal to the number rolled.

Spells Prepared:
- Scorching Ray
- Shatter</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Scorching Ray</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Shatter</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Battle Smith -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Battle Smith Specialist (Level 5)</name>
        <text>Extra Attack:
You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.

Spells Prepared:
- Branding Smite
- Warding Bond</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Branding Smite</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Warding Bond</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Cartographer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cartographer Specialist (Level 5)</name>
        <text>Guided Precision:
- Damage Boost: Once per turn, when you cast a Cartographer Spell or hit a creature affected by your Faerie Fire with an attack, you can add your Intelligence modifier to one damage roll of the spell or attack.
- Unwavering Focus: Taking damage cannot cause you to lose concentration on your Faerie Fire spell.

Spells Prepared:
- Locate Object
- Mind Spike</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Locate Object</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Mind Spike</spell>
      </feature>

      <slots>4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 6 -->
    <autolevel level="6">
      <feature>
        <name>Tool Expertise</name>
        <text>Double proficiency with tools.</text>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Infusions Known</name>
        <text>6 infusions known.</text>
        <choice name="Level 6 Infusions">
          <option>
            <name>Boots of the Winding Path</name>
            <text>Prerequisite: 6th-level artificer. While wearing these boots, a creature can use a bonus action to teleport up to 15 feet to an unoccupied space it can see, provided it has been in that space during the current turn.</text>
          </option>
          <option>
            <name>Radiant Weapon</name>
            <text>Prerequisite: 6th-level artificer. This magic weapon grants a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls. It can shed bright light, and has 4 charges to blind attackers using a reaction.</text>
          </option>
          <option>
            <name>Resistant Armor</name>
            <text>Prerequisite: 6th-level artificer. While wearing this armor, a creature has resistance to one damage type chosen when the infusion is applied.</text>
          </option>
        </choice>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 7 -->
    <autolevel level="7">
      <feature>
        <name>Flash of Genius</name>
        <text>Uses = Intelligence modifier per long rest.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 8 -->
    <autolevel level="8">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 9 -->
    <autolevel level="9">
      <!-- Alchemist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Specialist (Level 9)</name>
        <text>Restorative Reagents:
- Whenever a creature drinks an experimental elixir you created, the creature gains temporary hit points equal to 2d10 + your Intelligence modifier (minimum of 1 temporary hit point).
- You can cast lesser restoration without expending a spell slot and without providing the material component, provided you use alchemist's supplies as the spellcasting focus. You can do so a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Spells Prepared:
- Gaseous Form
- Mass Healing Word</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Gaseous Form</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Mass Healing Word</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Armorer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armorer Specialist (Level 9)</name>
        <text>Armor Modifications:
You learn how to use your infusions to specially modify your Arcane Armor. That armor now counts as four separate items for the purposes of your Infuse Item feature: armor (the chest piece), boots, helmet, and the armor's special weapon.
In addition, the maximum number of items you can infuse at once increases by 2, but those extra items must be part of your Arcane Armor.

Spells Prepared:
- Hypnotic Pattern
- Lightning Bolt</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Hypnotic Pattern</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Lightning Bolt</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Artillerist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artillerist Specialist (Level 9)</name>
        <text>Explosive Cannon:
Every eldritch cannon you create is now more destructive:
- The cannon's damage rolls all increase by 1d8.
- As an action, you can command the cannon to self-destruct if you are within 60 feet of it. Doing so forces each creature within 20 feet of it to make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 3d8 force damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. In addition, the cannon is destroyed.

Spells Prepared:
- Fireball
- Wind Wall</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Fireball</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Wind Wall</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Battle Smith -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Battle Smith Specialist (Level 9)</name>
        <text>Arcane Jolt:
You've learned how to channel magical energy to cause either harm or healing. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a magic weapon attack, or when your steel defender hits a creature, you can cause one of the following effects:
- The target takes an extra 2d6 force damage.
- Choose one creature or object you can see within 30 feet of the target. Healing energy flows into it, restoring 2d6 hit points to it.
You can use this energy a number of times equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of once), and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.

Spells Prepared:
- Aura of Vitality
- Conjure Barrage</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Aura of Vitality</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Conjure Barrage</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Cartographer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cartographer Specialist (Level 9)</name>
        <text>Ingenious Movement:
When you use your Flash of Genius feature, you or a willing creature you can see within 30 feet can teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see as part of the same reaction.

Spells Prepared:
- Call Lightning
- Clairvoyance</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Call Lightning</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Clairvoyance</spell>
      </feature>

      <slots>4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 10 -->
    <autolevel level="10">
      <feature>
        <name>Magic Item Adept</name>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Infusions Known</name>
        <text>8 infusions known.</text>
        <choice name="Level 10 Infusions">
          <option>
            <name>Helm of Awareness</name>
            <text>Prerequisite: 10th-level artificer. While wearing this helm, a creature has advantage on initiative rolls, and the wearer can't be surprised, provided they aren't incapacitated.</text>
          </option>
        </choice>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Infused Items</name>
        <text>3 active infusions.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 11 -->
    <autolevel level="11">
      <feature>
        <name>Spell-Storing Item</name>
        <text>Store a 1st or 2nd level spell.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 12 -->
    <autolevel level="12">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 13 -->
    <autolevel level="13">
      <!-- Alchemist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Specialist (Level 13)</name>
        <text>Spells Prepared:
- Blight
- Death Ward</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Blight</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Death Ward</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Armorer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armorer Specialist (Level 13)</name>
        <text>Spells Prepared:
- Fire Shield
- Greater Invisibility</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Fire Shield</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Greater Invisibility</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Artillerist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artillerist Specialist (Level 13)</name>
        <text>Spells Prepared:
- Ice Storm
- Wall of Fire</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Ice Storm</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Wall of Fire</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Battle Smith -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Battle Smith Specialist (Level 13)</name>
        <text>Spells Prepared:
- Aura of Purity
- Fire Shield</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Aura of Purity</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Fire Shield</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Cartographer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cartographer Specialist (Level 13)</name>
        <text>Spells Prepared:
- Banishment
- Locate Creature</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Banishment</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Locate Creature</spell>
      </feature>

      <slots>4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 14 -->
    <autolevel level="14">
      <feature>
        <name>Magic Item Savant</name>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Infusions Known</name>
        <text>10 infusions known.</text>
        <choice name="Level 14 Infusions">
          <option>
            <name>Arcane Propellant Armor</name>
            <text>Prerequisite: 14th-level artificer, An armor. While wearing this armor, a creature's walking speed increases by 5 feet, and the armor's gauntlets deal 1d8 force damage on a hit, which count as magic melee weapons.</text>
          </option>
        </choice>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 15 -->
    <autolevel level="15">
      <!-- Alchemist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Alchemist Specialist (Level 15)</name>
        <text>Chemical Mastery:
Your chemical exposure has armed you with great immunities:
- You gain resistance to acid damage and poison damage, and you are immune to the poisoned condition.
- You can cast greater restoration and heal once each without expending a spell slot and without providing material components, using alchemist's supplies as the spellcasting focus. You regain the ability to cast each spell in this way when you finish a long rest.

Spells Prepared:
- Cloudkill
- Raise Dead</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Cloudkill</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Raise Dead</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Armorer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Armorer Specialist (Level 15)</name>
        <text>Perfected Armor:
Your Arcane Armor gains additional benefits based on its model:
Guardian Model:
- When a creature you can see ends its turn within 30 feet of you, you can use your reaction to force the creature to make a Strength saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, you pull the creature up to 30 feet toward you to an unoccupied space. If you pull the creature into a space within 5 feet of you, you can make one melee weapon attack against it as part of this reaction. You can use this reaction a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
Infiltrator Model:
- Any creature that takes lightning damage from your Lightning Launcher glimmers with magical light until the start of your next turn. The glimmers provide 5 feet of dim light. Moreover, the glimmers grant advantage on the next attack roll against the target. If that attack hits, it deals an extra 1d6 lightning damage.

Spells Prepared:
- Passwall
- Wall of Force</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Passwall</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Wall of Force</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Artillerist -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Artillerist Specialist (Level 15)</name>
        <text>Fortified Position:
You're masters of battlefield fortification:
- You can now have two eldritch cannons active at the same time. You can create two cannons with the same action (spending spell slots as normal for the second), and you can activate both cannons with the same bonus action.
- You and your allies gain half cover (+2 AC and Dex saves) while within 10 feet of a cannon.

Spells Prepared:
- Cone of Cold
- Wall of Force</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Cone of Cold</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Wall of Force</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Battle Smith -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Battle Smith Specialist (Level 15)</name>
        <text>Improved Defender:
Your steel defender and arcane jolt are more powerful:
- The extra damage and healing of your Arcane Jolt increases to 4d6.
- Your steel defender gains a +2 bonus to Armor Class.
- Whenever your steel defender uses its Deflect Attack reaction, the attacker takes force damage equal to 1d4 + your Intelligence modifier.

Spells Prepared:
- Banishing Smite
- Mass Cure Wounds</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Banishing Smite</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Mass Cure Wounds</spell>
      </feature>

      <!-- Cartographer -->
      <feature optional="YES">
        <name>Cartographer Specialist (Level 15)</name>
        <text>Superior Atlas:
- Safe Haven: When a map holder is reduced to 0 HP (but not killed), they can destroy their map to instead have their HP become equal to twice your Artificer level, and teleport to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you or another map holder.
- Unerring Path: You can use your map to cast Find the Path without expending a spell slot. Once you use this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.

Spells Prepared:
- Scrying
- Teleportation Circle</text>
        <spell prepared="YES">Scrying</spell>
        <spell prepared="YES">Teleportation Circle</spell>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 16 -->
    <autolevel level="16">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 17 -->
    <autolevel level="17">
      <slots>4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 18 -->
    <autolevel level="18">
      <feature>
        <name>Magic Item Master</name>
      </feature>
      <feature>
        <name>Infused Items</name>
        <text>4 active infusions.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 19 -->
    <autolevel level="19">
      <feature>
        <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

    <!-- LEVEL 20 -->
    <autolevel level="20">
      <feature>
        <name>Soul of Artifice</name>
        <text>+1 to saves per attuned item; avoid dropping to 0 HP.</text>
      </feature>
    </autolevel>

  </class>

  <!-- ========================================== -->
  <!-- MAGIC ITEMS & MAGIC ITEM PLANS             -->
  <!-- ========================================== -->

  <!-- LEVEL 2 REPLICABLE ITEMS -->

  <item>
    <name>Bag of Holding</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>15</weight>
    <text>This bag has an interior space considerably larger than its outside dimensions, roughly 2 feet in diameter at the mouth and 4 feet deep. The bag can hold up to 500 pounds, not exceeding a volume of 64 cubic feet. The bag weighs 15 pounds, regardless of its contents. Retrieving an item from the bag requires an action.

If the bag is overloaded, pierced, or torn, it ruptures and is destroyed, and its contents are scattered in the Astral Plane. If the bag is turned inside out, its contents spill forth, unharmed, but the bag must be put right before it can be used again. Breathing creatures inside the bag can survive for up to 10 minutes, after which they begin to suffocate.

Placing a bag of holding inside an extradimensional space created by a handy haversack, portable hole, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Bag of Holding</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Bag of Holding.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Weaver's tools or Leatherworker's tools
- Component: Fine silk, a leather pouch, and a pinch of stardust or planar residue
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Cap of Water Breathing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <text>While wearing this cap, you can breathe underwater.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Cap of Water Breathing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Cap of Water Breathing.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Weaver's tools or Leatherworker's tools
- Component: Scale mail scrap or fish skin, and a pinch of dried kelp
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Goggles of Night</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>While wearing these dark lenses, you have darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, wearing the goggles increases its range by 60 feet.</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">darkvision +60</modifier>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Goggles of Night</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Goggles of Night.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Tinker's tools or Glassblower's tools
- Component: Two dark-tinted glass lenses, a brass frame, and a drop of owl's eyes or shadow essence
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Prosthetic Limb</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Common</detail>
    <text>This artificial limb replaces a lost hand, arm, foot, leg, or similar body part. It functions identically to the part it replaces. You can attach or detach it as an action.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Prosthetic Limb</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Common Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Prosthetic Limb.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Tinker's tools or Woodcarver's tools
- Component: Wooden or brass gearworks, leather bindings, and a minor energy focus
- Crafting Cost: 50 gp (25 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 5 hours (1.25 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Rope of Climbing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <text>This 60-foot rope can hold up to 3,000 pounds. As an action, you can command the rope to move, knot/unknot itself, or coil itself.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Rope of Climbing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Rope of Climbing.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Weaver's tools
- Component: Hemp or silk rope, and a drop of climbing beast's grease
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Sending Stones</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>These stones come in pairs. While touching one stone, you can cast the sending spell to target the bearer of the other stone (1/day).</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Sending Stones</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Sending Stones.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Mason's tools or Jeweler's tools
- Component: Two matching smooth stones, and a thread of communication magic or silver wire
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Wand of Magic Detection</name>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>This wand has 3 charges. While holding it, you can expend 1 charge to cast detect magic.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Wand of Magic Detection</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Wand of Magic Detection.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Woodcarver's tools or Jeweler's tools
- Component: A smooth wooden wand, and a drop of magical essence
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Wand of Secrets</name>
    <type>WD</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>This wand has 3 charges. While holding it, you can expend 1 charge to find the nearest secret door or trap within 30 feet.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Wand of Secrets</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Wand of Secrets.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Woodcarver's tools or Jeweler's tools
- Component: A rare wooden shaft, and a key or mechanism fragment
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <!-- LEVEL 6 REPLICABLE ITEMS -->

  <item>
    <name>Boots of Elvenkind</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>While wearing these boots, your steps make no sound, and you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks that rely on moving silently.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Boots of Elvenkind</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Boots of Elvenkind.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Cobbler's tools or Leatherworker's tools
- Component: Soft leather, elven silk, and silence-inducing magic
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Cloak of Elvenkind</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>While wearing this cloak, you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide, and Wisdom (Perception) checks made to see you have disadvantage.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Cloak of Elvenkind</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Cloak of Elvenkind.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Weaver's tools
- Component: Fine gray cloth, camouflaging pigments, and a drop of chameleon blood
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Gloves of Thievery</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <text>While wearing these gloves, you have a +5 bonus to Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) checks and Dexterity checks made to pick locks.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Gloves of Thievery</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Gloves of Thievery.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Leatherworker's tools
- Component: Supple mole or cat skin, and lubricant or grease
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Lantern of Revealing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>While lit, this lantern burns for 6 hours on 1 pint of oil, shedding bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. Invisible creatures and objects are visible while in the bright light.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Lantern of Revealing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Lantern of Revealing.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Smith's tools or Tinker's tools
- Component: Polished iron lantern frame, magnifying glass, and a pinch of truesight dust
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Pipes of Haunting</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>These pipes have 3 charges. You can use an action to play them and expend 1 charge, forcing each creature within 30 feet to make a DC 15 Wisdom save or become frightened for 1 minute.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Pipes of Haunting</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Pipes of Haunting.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Woodcarver's tools
- Component: Carved reeds, skull or bone fragments, and shadow realm resonance
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Ring of Water Walking</name>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <text>While wearing this ring, you can stand on and move across any liquid surface as if it were solid ground.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Ring of Water Walking</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Ring of Water Walking.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: A coral or blue gold ring band, and water elemental residue
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <!-- LEVEL 10 REPLICABLE ITEMS -->

  <item>
    <name>Boots of Striding and Springing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>While wearing these boots, your speed is 30 feet if it is not already higher, and your jump distance is tripled.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Boots of Striding and Springing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Boots of Striding and Springing.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Cobbler's tools
- Component: Heavy leather, springs or metal wires, and essence of a jumping beast
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Boots of the Winterlands</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>You gain resistance to cold damage, ignore difficult terrain created by ice or snow, and can tolerate temperatures as low as -50 degrees.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Boots of the Winterlands</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Boots of the Winterlands.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Cobbler's tools
- Component: Polar bear fur, winter wolf hide, and frost magic
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Bracers of Archery</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>While wearing these bracers, you have proficiency with the longbow and shortbow, and you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with those weapons.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Bracers of Archery</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Bracers of Archery.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Leatherworker's tools or Smith's tools
- Component: Stiffened leather plates, gold inlays, and an archer's focal rune
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Brooch of Shielding</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>While wearing this brooch, you have resistance to force damage, and you are immune to damage from the magic missile spell.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Brooch of Shielding</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Brooch of Shielding.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Brass or bronze plate, a defensive crystal, and shield spell resonance
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Cloak of Protection</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>You gain a +1 bonus to AC and saving throws while wearing this cloak.</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">saving throws +1</modifier>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Cloak of Protection</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Cloak of Protection.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Weaver's tools
- Component: Sturdy fabric, silver thread, and a defensive protective rune or essence
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Eyes of the Eagle</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>These crystal lenses fit over your eyes. While wearing them, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Eyes of the Eagle</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Eyes of the Eagle.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Glassblower's tools or Jeweler's tools
- Component: Two polished sapphire lenses, silver frames, and eagle eye extract
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Gauntlets of Ogre Power</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>Your Strength score is 19 while you wear these gauntlets. They have no effect on you if your Strength is already 19 or higher.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Gauntlets of Ogre Power</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Gauntlets of Ogre Power.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Smith's tools or Leatherworker's tools
- Component: Heavy steel plates, leather liner, and ogre blood or muscle fibers
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Gloves of Missile Snaring</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>While wearing these gloves, you can reduce the damage of a ranged weapon attack against you by 1d10 + your Dexterity modifier as a reaction. If you reduce the damage to 0, you can catch the missile.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Gloves of Missile Snaring</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Gloves of Missile Snaring.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Leatherworker's tools
- Component: Flexible deerskin gloves, silk weaving, and kinetic deflection runes
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Hat of Disguise</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>While wearing this hat, you can use an action to cast the disguise self spell from it at will.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Hat of Disguise</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Hat of Disguise.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Weaver's tools
- Component: Fabric hat, illusion dust, and a drop of doppleganger blood
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Headband of Intellect</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>Your Intelligence score is 19 while you wear this headband. It has no effect on you if your Intelligence is already 19 or higher.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Headband of Intellect</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Headband of Intellect.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools or Tinker's tools
- Component: A brass or silver band, a polished sapphire, and a page from an ancient tome of lore or sage's brain essence
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Helm of Comprehending Languages</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon</detail>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <text>While wearing this helmet, you can use an action to cast the comprehend languages spell from it at will.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Helm of Comprehending Languages</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Helm of Comprehending Languages.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Smith's tools
- Component: Polished iron helm, gold leaf inscriptions, and a spellbook fragment
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Medallion of Thoughts</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>This medallion has 3 charges. While wearing it, you can expend 1 charge to cast detect thoughts.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Medallion of Thoughts</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Medallion of Thoughts.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Silver medallion, a polished copper backing, and telepathic essence
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Necklace of Adaptation</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>While wearing this necklace, you can breathe normally in any environment, and you have advantage on saving throws against harmful gases and vapors.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Necklace of Adaptation</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Necklace of Adaptation.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Gold chain, silver leaf pendant, and planar protective dust
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Periapt of Wound Closure</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>While you wear this pendant, you stabilize automatically at the start of your turn if you are dying. In addition, when you roll a Hit Die to regain hit points, you double the number of hit points restored.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Periapt of Wound Closure</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Periapt of Wound Closure.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Silver chain, a polished ruby, and troll blood or cellular essence
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Pipes of the Sewers</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>These pipes have 3 charges. You can use an action to play them and expend 1 charge to summon and command swarms of rats.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Pipes of the Sewers</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Pipes of the Sewers.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Woodcarver's tools
- Component: Carved bone or wood, rat whiskers, and sewer residue
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Ring of Jumping</name>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>While wearing this ring, you can cast the jump spell from it at will, targeting only yourself.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Ring of Jumping</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Ring of Jumping.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Copper ring band, jump spell scroll fragment, and grasshopper essence
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Ring of Mind Shielding</name>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>While wearing this ring, you are immune to magic that allows other creatures to read your thoughts, determine whether you are lying, know your alignment, or learn your creature type.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Ring of Mind Shielding</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Ring of Mind Shielding.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Lead-lined silver ring, a tiny sapphire, and a thought-blocking focus
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Slippers of Spider Climbing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>While wearing these slippers, you can move up, down, and across vertical surfaces and upside down along ceilings, while leaving your hands free.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Slippers of Spider Climbing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Slippers of Spider Climbing.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Cobbler's tools
- Component: Soft silk slippers, spider web silk, and wall-adhering alchemy
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Ventilating Lungs</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>These prosthetic lungs replace your lungs. You can breathe normally in any environment, and you are immune to being poisoned by gas.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Ventilating Lungs</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Ventilating Lungs.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Smith's tools or Tinker's tools
- Component: Tiny brass bellows, gold filters, and air-purifying elemental essence
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Winged Boots</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>While you wear these boots, you have a flying speed equal to your walking speed. You can use the boots to fly for up to 4 hours, all at once or in several shorter flights, each one using at least 1 minute from the duration. If you are flying when the duration expires, you descend in a gentle glide for 1 minute (30 feet per round), landing safely. If you haven't landed by then, you fall the remaining distance.

The boots regain 2 hours of flying capability for every 12 hours they aren't in use.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Winged Boots</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Uncommon Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Winged Boots.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Cobbler's tools or Leatherworker's tools
- Component: Fine leather boots, feathers from a flying creature (e.g., giant eagle or griffon), and air elemental vapor
- Crafting Cost: 200 gp (100 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 20 hours (5 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <!-- LEVEL 14 REPLICABLE ITEMS -->

  <item>
    <name>Amulet of Health</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>Your Constitution score is 19 while you wear this amulet. It has no effect on you if your Constitution is already 19 or higher.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Amulet of Health</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct an Amulet of Health.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools or Smith's tools
- Component: A gold chain and medallion, a polished ruby, and blood or heart essence of a hardy creature (e.g., bear or giant)
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Belt of Hill Giant Strength</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <text>Your Strength score is 21 while you wear this belt. It has no effect on you if your Strength is already 21 or higher.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Belt of Hill Giant Strength</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Belt of Hill Giant Strength.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Leatherworker's tools or Smith's tools
- Component: Thick giant leather hide, a heavy iron buckle, and blood or bone of a hill giant
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Boots of Speed</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>While wearing these boots, you can use a bonus action to click their heels. Doing so doubles your walking speed, and any opportunity attacks against you have disadvantage.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Boots of Speed</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Boots of Speed.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Cobbler's tools
- Component: Supple leather boots, cheetah or quick beast claws, and haste spell scroll fragment
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Bracers of Defense</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>While wearing these bracers, you gain a +2 bonus to AC if you are wearing no armor and using no shield.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Bracers of Defense</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Bracers of Defense.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Leatherworker's tools or Smith's tools
- Component: Fine leather, gold filigree, and a mage armor focal rune
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Cloak of the Bat</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>While wearing this cloak, you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. While in dim light or darkness, you can fly at a speed of 40 feet.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Cloak of the Bat</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Cloak of the Bat.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Weaver's tools
- Component: Dark bat wings or fine dark cloth, and bat salivary extract
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Dimensional Shackles</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare</detail>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <text>You can use an action to place these shackles on an incapacitated creature. The shackled creature cannot teleport or travel extradimensionally.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Dimensional Shackles</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct Dimensional Shackles.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Smith's tools
- Component: Cold iron shackles, dimensional anchor runes, and a drop of planar dust
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Gem of Seeing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>This gem has 3 charges. You can speak its command word and expend 1 charge to gain truesight out to 120 feet for 10 minutes.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Gem of Seeing</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Gem of Seeing.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Polished diamond or sapphire focus, gold casing, and truesight spell resonance
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Horn of Blasting</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare</detail>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>You can use an action to blow this horn, creating a 30-foot cone of sonic energy. Each creature in the cone must make a DC 15 Constitution save or take 5d6 thunder damage and be deafened.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Horn of Blasting</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Horn of Blasting.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Smith's tools or Woodcarver's tools
- Component: Brass or horn frame, and sonic resonance focus
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Ring of Free Action</name>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>While wearing this ring, you ignore difficult terrain, and spells or other effects cannot reduce your speed or cause you to be paralyzed or restrained.</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Ring of Free Action</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Ring of Free Action.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Silver ring band, freedom of movement spell scroll, and mercury drop
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Ring of Protection</name>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>You gain a +1 bonus to AC and saving throws while wearing this ring.</text>
    <modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
    <modifier category="bonus">saving throws +1</modifier>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Ring of Protection</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Ring of Protection.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Gold ring band, shield rune engraving, and protective focus
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Ring of the Ram</name>
    <type>RG</type>
    <magic>1</magic>
    <detail>Rare (requires attunement)</detail>
    <text>This ring has 3 charges. You can use an action to expend 1 to 3 charges to strike a creature within 60 feet with a spectral ram's head (deals 2d10 force damage per charge expended and knocks the target back).</text>
  </item>

  <item>
    <name>Recipe: Ring of the Ram</name>
    <type>G</type>
    <magic>0</magic>
    <detail>Rare Recipe</detail>
    <weight>0</weight>
    <text>A detailed crafting plan, formula, or recipe explaining how to construct a Ring of the Ram.

Requirements:
- Tool Proficiency: Jeweler's tools
- Component: Gold ring band with carved ram horn shape, and ram bone or spirit focus
- Crafting Cost: 2,000 gp (1,000 gp if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)
- Crafting Time: 200 hours (50 hours if crafted by a Level 10+ Artificer)</text>
  </item>

  <!-- ========================================== -->
  <!-- CHARACTER BACKGROUNDS                      -->
  <!-- ========================================== -->

  <background>
    <name>House Agent (House Cannith)</name>
    <proficiency>Investigation, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You have sworn fealty to House Cannith, the Dragonmarked House of Making. You serve as the eyes and hands of your house, performing missions that range from finding ancient Schema in Xen'drik ruins to securing trade agreements or defending house enclaves.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Investigation, Persuasion</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Alchemist's supplies, tinker's tools</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Equipment</name>
      <text>A set of fine clothes, the signet ring of House Cannith, identification papers, and a pouch containing 20 gp.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: House Connection</name>
      <text>As an agent of your house, you can always get food and lodging for yourself and your friends at a House Cannith enclave. When the house assigns you a mission, it will usually provide you with the necessary supplies and transportation. Beyond this, you have many old friends, mentors, and rivals in your house, and you may encounter one of them when you interact with a house business.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Suggested Role</name>
      <text>Choose or roll a d8 to determine your role in the house:
1 | Acquisition (Acquiring resources or artifacts)
2 | Investigation (Solving mysteries or uncovering threats)
3 | Research &amp; Development (Designing new magical technology)
4 | Security (Protecting enclaves or VIPs)
5 | Intimidation (Enforcing house policy or collecting debts)
6 | Exploration (Mapping new ruins or lost domains)
7 | Negotiation (Brokering agreements or diplomatic deals)
8 | Covert Operations (Infiltration and corporate espionage)</text>
    </trait>
  </background>

  <background>
    <name>Guild Artisan</name>
    <proficiency>Insight, Persuasion</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You are a member of an artisan's guild, trained in a particular craft and initiated into the secrets of your guild's guildmasters. You might be a smith, a glassblower, a weaver, or any other type of skilled creator.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>Insight, Persuasion</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
      <text>One type of artisan's tools of your choice</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>One of your choice</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Equipment</name>
      <text>A set of artisan's tools (one of your choice), a letter of introduction from your guild, a set of traveler's clothes, and a pouch containing 15 gp.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Guild Membership</name>
      <text>As an established and respected member of a guild, you can rely on certain benefits that membership provides. Your fellow guild members will provide you with lodging and food if necessary, and pay for your funeral if needed. In some cities, a guildhall offers a central place to meet other members of your profession, which can be a good place to meet potential patrons, allies, or rumors.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>

  <background>
    <name>Sage</name>
    <proficiency>History, Arcana</proficiency>
    <trait>
      <name>Description</name>
      <text>You spent years learning the lore of the multiverse. You scoured manuscripts, studied scrolls, and listened to the greatest experts on the subjects that interest you. Your efforts have made you a master in your fields of study.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
      <text>History, Arcana</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Languages</name>
      <text>Two of your choice</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Equipment</name>
      <text>A bottle of black ink, a quill, a small knife, a letter from a dead colleague posing a question you have not yet been able to answer, a set of common clothes, and a pouch containing 10 gp.</text>
    </trait>
    <trait>
      <name>Feature: Researcher</name>
      <text>When you attempt to learn or recall a piece of lore, if you do not know that information, you often know where and from whom you can obtain it. Usually, this information resides in a library, scriptorium, university, or a sage or other learned person or creature. Your DM might rule that the knowledge you seek is secreted away in an almost inaccessible place, or that it simply cannot be found.</text>
    </trait>
  </background>

  <!-- ========================================== -->
  <!-- ARTIFICER MINIONS & COMPANIONS             -->
  <!-- ========================================== -->

  <monster>
    <name>Steel Defender</name>
    <size>M</size>
    <type>Construct</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>2 + your Intelligence modifier + 5 * Artificer Level</hp>
    <speed>40 ft.</speed>
    <str>14</str>
    <dex>12</dex>
    <con>14</con>
    <int>4</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>6</cha>
    <savingThrows>Dex, Con</savingThrows>
    <skills>Athletics, Perception</skills>
    <damageImmunities>Poison</damageImmunities>
    <conditionImmunities>Charmed, Exhaustion, Poisoned</conditionImmunities>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft., Passive Perception 14</senses>
    <languages>Understands languages you speak</languages>
    <trait>
      <name>Vigilant</name>
      <text>The defender can't be surprised.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Force-Empowered Rend</name>
      <text>Melee Weapon Attack: your spell attack modifier to hit, reach 5 ft., one target you can see. Hit: 1d8 + PB force damage.</text>
    </action>
    <action>
      <name>Repair (3/Day)</name>
      <text>The magical mechanisms inside the defender restore 2d8 + PB hit points to itself or to one construct or object within 5 feet of it.</text>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Deflect Attack</name>
      <text>The defender imposes disadvantage on the attack roll of one creature it can see within 5 feet of it, provided the attack roll is against a creature other than the defender.</text>
    </reaction>
  </monster>

  <monster>
    <name>Homunculus Servant</name>
    <size>T</size>
    <type>Construct</type>
    <alignment>Neutral</alignment>
    <ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
    <hp>1 + your Intelligence modifier + Artificer Level</hp>
    <speed>20 ft., fly 30 ft.</speed>
    <str>4</str>
    <dex>15</dex>
    <con>12</con>
    <int>10</int>
    <wis>10</wis>
    <cha>7</cha>
    <savingThrows>Dex</savingThrows>
    <skills>Perception, Stealth</skills>
    <damageImmunities>Poison</damageImmunities>
    <conditionImmunities>Exhaustion, Poisoned</conditionImmunities>
    <senses>Darkvision 60 ft., Passive Perception 14</senses>
    <languages>Understands languages you speak</languages>
    <trait>
      <name>Evasion</name>
      <text>If the homunculus is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, it instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the saving throw, and only half damage if it fails. It can't use this trait if it's incapacitated.</text>
    </trait>
    <action>
      <name>Force Strike</name>
      <text>Ranged Weapon Attack: your spell attack modifier to hit, range 30 ft., one target you can see. Hit: 1d4 + PB force damage.</text>
    </action>
    <reaction>
      <name>Channel Magic</name>
      <text>The homunculus delivers a spell you cast that has a range of touch. The homunculus must be within 120 feet of you.</text>
    </reaction>
  </monster>

  <!-- ========================================== -->
  <!-- FEATS RELEVANT TO ARTIFICER                -->
  <!-- ========================================== -->

  <!-- STANDARD FEATS -->

  <feat>
    <name>War Caster</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast at least one spell</prerequisite>
    <text>You have practiced performing magic in the midst of combat, learning techniques that grant you the following benefits:
- You have advantage on Constitution saving throws that you make to maintain your concentration on a spell when you take damage.
- You can perform the somatic components of spells even when you have weapons or a shield in one or both hands.
- When a hostile creature's movement provokes an opportunity attack from you, you can use your reaction to cast a spell at the creature, rather than making an opportunity attack. The spell must have a casting time of 1 action and must target only that creature.</text>
  </feat>

  <feat>
    <name>Fey Touched</name>
    <text>Your exposure to the Feywild has magic-infused you, granting you the following benefits:
- Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.
- You learn the misty step spell and one 1st-level spell of your choice. The 1st-level spell must be from the divination or enchantment school. You can cast each of these spells once without expending a spell slot per long rest, or cast them using your normal spell slots. Your spellcasting ability for these spells is the ability score increased by this feat.</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">Intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>

  <feat>
    <name>Shadow Touched</name>
    <text>Your exposure to the Shadowfell has magic-infused you, granting you the following benefits:
- Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.
- You learn the invisibility spell and one 1st-level spell of your choice. The 1st-level spell must be from the illusion or necromancy school. You can cast each of these spells once without expending a spell slot per long rest, or cast them using your normal spell slots. Your spellcasting ability for these spells is the ability score increased by this feat.</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">Intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>

  <feat>
    <name>Telekinetic</name>
    <text>You learn to move things with your mind, granting you the following benefits:
- Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.
- You learn the mage hand cantrip. If you already know it, its range increases by 30 feet. You can cast it without somatic or verbal components, and the hand is invisible.
- As a bonus action, you can try to telekinetically shove one creature you can see within 30 feet of you. When you do so, the target must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your spellcasting ability modifier) or be moved 5 feet toward you or away from you. A willing creature can choose to fail this saving throw.</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">Intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>

  <feat>
    <name>Telepathic</name>
    <text>You awaken the ability to mentally connect with others, granting you the following benefits:
- Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.
- You can speak telepathically to any creature you can see within 60 feet of you.
- You can cast the detect thoughts spell once without expending a spell slot per long rest. Your spellcasting ability for this spell is the ability score increased by this feat.</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">Intelligence +1</modifier>
  </feat>

  <feat>
    <name>Elemental Adept</name>
    <prerequisite>The ability to cast at least one spell</prerequisite>
    <text>Prerequisite: The ability to cast at least one spell.
When you gain this feat, choose one of the following damage types: acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder.
Spells you cast ignore resistance to damage of the chosen type. In addition, when you roll damage for a spell you cast that deals damage of that type, you can treat any 1 on a damage die as a 2.</text>
  </feat>

  <feat>
    <name>Sharpshooter</name>
    <text>You have mastered ranged weapons and can make shots that others find impossible. You gain the following benefits:
- Attacking at long range doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.
- Your ranged weapon attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover.
- Before you make an attack with a ranged weapon that you are proficient with, you can choose to take a -5 penalty to the attack roll. If the attack hits, you add +10 to the attack's damage.</text>
  </feat>

  <feat>
    <name>Medium Armor Master</name>
    <prerequisite>Proficiency with medium armor</prerequisite>
    <text>You have practiced moving in medium armor to gain the following benefits:
- Wearing medium armor doesn't impose disadvantage on your Dexterity (Stealth) checks.
- When you wear medium armor, you can add 3, rather than 2, to your Armor Class if you have a Dexterity score of 16 or higher.</text>
  </feat>

  <!-- EBERRON-SPECIFIC FEATS -->

  <feat>
    <name>Aberrant Dragonmark (Eberron)</name>
    <text>You have manifested an aberrant dragonmark - a flawed, involuntary, and unpredictable mark that grants you minor magical power. You gain the following benefits:
- Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.
- You learn a cantrip of your choice from the sorcerer spell list. In addition, you learn a 1st-level spell from the same list. You can cast this 1st-level spell once per short or long rest. Constitution is your spellcasting ability for these spells.
- When you cast the 1st-level spell through your mark, you can expend one of your Hit Dice and roll it. If you roll an even number, you gain temporary hit points equal to the number rolled. If you roll an odd number, one creature of your choice within 30 feet of you takes force damage equal to the number rolled (or you take the damage if no other creature is near).</text>
    <modifier category="ability score">Constitution +1</modifier>
  </feat>

  <feat>
    <name>Revenant Blade (Eberron)</name>
    <prerequisite>Elf</prerequisite>
    <text>You are a master of the double-bladed scimitar, wielding it with lethal elegance. You gain the following benefits:
- Increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.
- While you are wielding a double-bladed scimitar with two hands, you gain a +1 bonus to Armor Class.
- A double-bladed scimitar has the finesse property when you wield it.</text>
    <modifier category="ac">+1</modifier>
  </feat>

  <feat>
    <name>Greater Dragonmark (Eberron)</name>
    <prerequisite>A character with a Dragonmark of at least 5th level</prerequisite>
    <text>Your dragonmark has manifested into a powerful, complex sigil, unlocking its full potential. You gain the following benefits:
- Increase the ability score associated with your subrace's dragonmark by 1, to a maximum of 20.
- Your dragonmark's Intuition Die increases by one step (e.g., d4 to d6, d6 to d8).
- You learn one high-level spell associated with your House's dragonmark, which you can cast once per long rest without expending a spell slot.</text>
  </feat>

</compendium>
